Marcelo Augusto

SKILLS

Javascript · Typescript · Vue.js · React.js \cdot Node.js \cdot GraphQL \cdot GraphQL \cdot Nest.js · Next.js · Angular · HTML · CSS · CSS3 · TailwindCss · PostgreSQL · MySQL · MongoDB · AWS · Firebase · PHP · Laravel · Python · Docker ·

Blockchain · Web3 · Smart Contracts

Senior Full Stack Developer (Javascript, Vue.js, React.js, Node.js)

SUMMARY

Marcelo is a senior software engineer with over 13 years of experience working with various technologies and programming languages. Specializing in React, Vue, and other modern frameworks. Marcelo is also a seasoned tech lead, spearheading developers' work and showing the right path to follow on projects' architecture and development.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Full-stack Developer

02/2022 - 03/2024

Liquid Compass

San Francisco, CA

- Documented the entire system thoroughly during my first trimester and was able to assist the newly-hired tech leader in creating a successful modernization project plan.
- Created a solution using React, Vue and Node.js to import thousands of users via XLSX file import.
- Worked on integrating the modernization project with the legacy codebase in a phased manner, with no significant risk to the company's product.
- Technologies: Javascript, Typescript, React.js, Vue.js, Angular, Node.js, Nest, Next.js, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS, GraphQL, Docker, HTML, CSS, CSS3, TailwindCss.

Senior Front-end Vue Engineer

06/2020 - 01/2022

Intelipost

United Kingdom

- Helped with punctual front-end demands inside the company platform available to
- Participated in clients' migration from AngularJS framework to a version using Vue.
- Worked on bug fixing depending on sprint performance.
- Technologies: JavaScript, Vue, AngularJS, GraphQL, MongoDB, UI Components, Node.js, REST APIs, REST, Databases, APIs, Web Development, HTML, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Design (RWD), CSS3, ECMAScript (ES6), DOM, JSON, Full-stack, Google Maps, Google SEO, User Experience (UX), Front-end Development, Material UI, Vanilla JS

Senior Full-stack Engineer

04/2018 - 11/2019

Techmid

- Acted as an advisor to help managers gain knowledge about software explanation to clients and the path to pursue.
- Fixed bugs and created new features for projects that came to the company.
- Participated in a project that aimed to decrease the export time from hours to seconds with sheets automation.
- Technologies: JavaScript, PHP, CakePHP 3, HTML5, CSS, CodeIgniter 3, UI Components, REST APIs, REST, Databases, APIs, Web Development, jQuery, HTML, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Design (RWD), CSS3, Responsive Email Templates, Email Templates, DOM, Full-stack, Google SEO, PHP 7, Front-end Development, Vanilla JS, Sass, DevOps, Full-stack Development, Integration, GitHub, JSON REST APIs, Google Tag Manager, Front-end, Back-end, RSS Feeds

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science **ESAMC Santos**

02/2014 - 08/2018

Santos, São Paulo